<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Infosec MNIT</title><link>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Infosec MNIT</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unleash The Power of Web3 &amp; Open Source</title><link>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/blog/post2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/blog/post2/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In this article, we will highlight the Infosec Club at MNIT Jaipur&amp;rsquo;s successful training session titled &amp;ldquo;Unleash The Power of Web3 &amp;amp; Open Source,&amp;rdquo; which took place on October 8, 2023. The event aimed to empower participants with a comprehensive understanding of Web3 and open-source technologies.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="event-details">Event Details&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date:&lt;/strong> October 8, 2023&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Timing:&lt;/strong> 10:00 AM to 3:00 PM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Venue:&lt;/strong> Neeti Sabhagar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Total Participation:&lt;/strong> 82&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="objective-and-outcome">Objective and Outcome&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The training session &amp;ldquo;Unleash The Power of Web3 &amp;amp; Open Source&amp;rdquo; achieved its primary objective by empowering attendees with a comprehensive understanding of Web3 and open-source technologies. The event educated participants about the core concepts of Web3 and emphasized the significance of open-source principles in driving innovation and collaboration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key Outcomes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Understanding Web3&lt;/strong>: Participants gained valuable insights into Web3&amp;rsquo;s fundamentals, including blockchain technology and decentralized applications. They learned about its potential applications across various industries.
&lt;img src="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/static/web3_image1.jpg" alt="Alt Text" style="width:50%; display: grid;">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hands-On Experience&lt;/strong>: Participants deployed their first storage smart contract on the Nordek blockchain (Open source).
&lt;img src="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/static/web3_image3.jpg" alt="Alt Text" style="width:50%; display: grid;">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Open Source Contributions&lt;/strong>: They developed their portfolio using Fastn Network and made their first open-source contribution.
&lt;img src="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/static/web3_image2.jpg" alt="Alt Text" style="width:50%; display: grid;">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The feedback received from attendees was overwhelmingly positive, with participants expressing increased awareness of Web3&amp;rsquo;s potential and the importance of open-source principles. The event successfully empowered individuals to harness the power of Web3 and open source for a more decentralized and innovative digital landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The success of the training session &amp;ldquo;Unleash The Power of Web3 &amp;amp; Open Source&amp;rdquo; is a testament to the dedication and hard work of the Infosec Club at MNIT Jaipur. We are proud of our achievements and look forward to organizing more such impactful events in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By celebrating this successful event, we can inspire and motivate our members to continue driving innovation and collaboration in the world of Web3 and open source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Basics Of Cybersecurity by INFOSEC CLUB</title><link>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/blog/post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 17:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/blog/post/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In this article, we will spotlight the successful workshop organized by the Infosec Club at MNIT Jaipur titled &amp;ldquo;Basics Of Cybersecurity.&amp;rdquo; The workshop took place on September 9, 2023, with the aim of empowering students with essential cybersecurity knowledge and hands-on experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="event-details">Event Details&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Date:&lt;/strong> September 9, 2023&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Timing:&lt;/strong> 5:00 PM to 6:30 PM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Venue:&lt;/strong> VLTC - L007&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Total Participation:&lt;/strong> 63&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="objective-and-outcome">Objective and Outcome&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The workshop &amp;ldquo;Basics Of Cybersecurity&amp;rdquo; by the Infosec Club at MNIT Jaipur was designed to raise awareness about the importance of cybersecurity in our digitally connected world. It aimed to equip participants with practical skills to protect themselves online and foster a culture of online safety.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Key Outcomes:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fundamental Knowledge&lt;/strong>: The workshop successfully achieved its goal of educating students on the fundamentals of cybersecurity. Participants gained insights into common cyber threats and best practices for safeguarding their digital lives.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;img src="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/static/cyber_security_image3.jpg" alt="Alt Text" style="width:50%; display: grid;">
&lt;ol start="2">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Hands-On Experience&lt;/strong>: Through interactive activities, attendees gained practical experience in dealing with cybersecurity challenges.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;img src="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/static/cyber_security_image1.jpg" alt="Alt Text" style="width:50%; display: grid;">
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Networking and Knowledge Sharing&lt;/strong>: The workshop provided a platform for networking and knowledge sharing among participants. It encouraged them to engage in ongoing cybersecurity discussions and stay vigilant in their online activities.
The event received positive feedback, with participants expressing increased confidence in their ability to identify and mitigate cyber risks.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;img src="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/static/cyber_security_image2.jpg" alt="Alt Text" style="width:50%; display: grid;">
&lt;h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The success of the workshop &amp;ldquo;Basics Of Cybersecurity&amp;rdquo; is a testament to the Infosec Club&amp;rsquo;s dedication to raising awareness and fostering cybersecurity skills among students. We are proud of our achievements and look forward to organizing more informative and interactive events in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By celebrating this successful workshop, we can inspire and motivate our members to continue their journey toward a safer and more secure digital world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Members</title><link>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/members/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rohit Dhill (@s4dr0t1)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divyansh Rawat (@d-raw)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pranshu Khandal (@calx)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sachin Kumar Dhaka (@s4ch)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Abhishek Basniwal (@akbasniwal)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/resources/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="add-resources-here">Add Resources Here&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>🛡️ About Us</title><link>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://infosec-mnit.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Welcome to the Guardians of the Digital Realm!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At MNIT, our InfoSec Club is more than just a club; it&amp;rsquo;s a sanctuary for digital adventurers, where you become the hero of your cybersecurity journey. 🚀&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="-who-we-are">🕵️‍♂️ Who We Are&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re a tight-knit community of ethical hackers, crypto warriors, and cybersecurity champions, fueled by curiosity and a shared mission – safeguarding the digital world. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a coding novice or a security guru, you belong here. Together, we&amp;rsquo;re forging a safer online future.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="-what-we-do">💼 What We Do&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Cybersecurity Workshops&lt;/strong>: Immerse yourself in hands-on workshops, led by experts, to sharpen your skills in ethical hacking, network defense, cryptography, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Capture the Flag Challenges&lt;/strong>: Get ready for adrenaline-pumping capture the flag (CTF) competitions where you can outsmart opponents and claim the title of InfoSec Maestro.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Guest Hackers&lt;/strong>: We bring in renowned cybersecurity maestros to reveal their secrets, share war stories, and ignite your passion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Securing the Future&lt;/strong>: Our collective knowledge and actions not only protect us but also influence the security of the digital universe.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="-get-involved">🔗 Get Involved&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Are you ready to join the ranks of the InfoSec superheroes? Here&amp;rsquo;s how:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Explore our &lt;a href="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/content/blog/_index.md">Events&lt;/a> to discover what we do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Uncover hidden knowledge in our treasure trove of &lt;a href="https://infosec-mnit.github.io/content/resources.md">Resources&lt;/a>, including tutorials, tools, and learning materials.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Join our elite &lt;a href="https://discord.gg/SzES6fBg">Discord Guild&lt;/a> and team up with fellow defenders of the web.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="-contact-us">📬 Contact Us&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Got questions or eager to dive in? Reach out to us at &lt;a href="mailto:2021uec1454@mnit.ac.in">info@mnit-infosecclub.com&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stay up-to-date with our missions and cybersecurity news by following us on &lt;a href="https://x.com/infosecmnitj">Twitter&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://instagram.com/infosec.mnit">Instagram&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prepare to embark on an epic quest in the world of information security and join us in our mission to be the guardians of the digital realm! Together, we&amp;rsquo;ll ensure that the digital future remains safe and secure. 💻🛡️🌐&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>